Guide to the Wallace Earle Stegner conservation collection, 1956-1974
Department of Special Collections
Wallace Earle Stegner conservation collection,
1956-1974
Special Collections M0241
Stegner, Wallace Earle, 1909-
3 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Restricted access: requires 24 hour paging period.
Provenance
Gift of Wallace Stegner, 1973.
Biographical Note
Wallace Earle Stegner was born in Lake Mills, Iowa, February 18, 1909. A prize winning novelist and author also of articles and short stories, Stegner has been a professor of English at Stanford University since 1945.
Scope and Content
This collection contains material all relating to conservation. It is all printed material - reports, articles, magazines etc. The collection covers a period from 1956 and 1959-1968 and 1970-1973. Includes one letter copied to W. Stegner which was an enclosure in a magazine.
Container List
- ADVISORY BOARD ON NATIONAL PARKS - HISTORIC SITES - BUILDINGS & MONUMENTS: MINUTES
  - 1. 1961, Sept. 15-19.45th meeting - Olympic National Park, Washington. Memo inserted - Conrad L. Wirth, Director National Park Service to the Interior, Nov. 17, 1961. (Box 1)
  - 2. 1962, April 30 - May 3.46th meeting - Washington, D.C. (Box 1)
  - 3. 1962, Oct. 15.-17.47th meeting - Hawaii Volcanoes National Park, Hawaii. (Box 1)
  - 4. 1963, March 25-27.48th meeting - Washington, D.C. (Box 1)
  - 5. 1963, Nov. 4-6.49th meeting - Big Bend National Park, Texas. (Box 1)
  - 6. 1964, April 13-16.50th meeting - Washington, D.C. (Box 1)
  - 7. 1964, Oct. 5-14.51st meeting - Shenadoah National Park, Blue Ridge Parkway, Great Smoky Mountains National Park. Inserts: 1) list of present and past board member, 2) map of the United States indicating active proposals and areas under study, 3) diagram charting the major legislation and public law - 89th Congress. (Box 1)
  - 8. 1965, April 12-15.52nd meeting - Washington, D.C. and Harpers Ferry, West Virginia. Insert: additional minutes of the 52nd meeting. (Box 1)
  - 9. 1965, Aug. 4,6,8 & Oct. 4-7.53rd meeting - Alaska, Washington, D.C. and Harpers Ferry, West Virginia. (Box 1)
  - 10. 1966, Oct. 3-6.55th meeting - Washington, D.C. (Box 1)
  - 11. 1967, April 17-19.56th meeting - Washington, D.C. (Box 1)
  - 12. 1967, Nov. 6-9.57th meeting - Washington, D.C. (Box 1)
  - 13. 1968, April 16-18.58th meeting - Washington, D.C. (Box 1)
  - 14. 1973, April 16-18.68th meeting - Washington, D.C. Insert: memo - Deputy Director National Park Service to Chairman, Members & Council Members, Advisory Board... 1973, June 27. (Box 1)
- REPORTS & ARTICLES
  - 1. Assembly Committee on Environmental Quality. Final Summary: 1971 Measures Referred to Assembly Committee on Environmental Quality. 1972, Jan. 3. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 2. Carlin, Alan and Hoehn, William E. The Grand Canyon Controversy - 1967: Further Economic Comparisons of Nuclear Alternatives. March 1967. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 3. Carlin, Alan. The Grand Canyon Controversy or How Reclamation Justifies the Unjustifiable. April 1967. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 4. Carlin, Alan. The Grand Canyon Controversy: Lessons for Federal Cost-Benefit Practices. Oct. 1967. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 5. Commerce, U.S. Department of. Manual - Scenic Roads and Parkways Study. Washington, D.C. 1964, Oct. 26. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 6. Daedalus, Vol. 96, No. 4. Reprint - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1967. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1. Greiff, Constance M., editor. Lost America from the Mississippi to the Pacific. Pyne Press, Princeton, 1972. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1. Interior, U.S. Department of. International Affairs Long Range Program. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 2. Interior, U.S. Department of. NPS Criteria for Parklane 1966. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 3. Macinko, George. Conservation Trends and the Future American Environment. Reprinted from the Biologist, Vol. 1, No. 1-2, January 1968. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 4. A University of the Forest Service. U.S. Government Printing Office, Washington, 1970. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 5. Atkins, T.H. and Olmsted, R.R. Life Styles and the Land. Reprinted from a special issue of The Sense of Security. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 6. Travel borchure on Colorado. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 7. Typescript - National Parks by Whitney Watriss with cover letter to Wallace Stegner from Richard N. Billings, Manager Director of National Tourism Resources Review Commission, March 1, 1973. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1. A New Park Concept - Summary. Report from the Dept. of Interior, Nat'l. Park Service with cover memo (xerox copy from George B. Hartzog Jr., Director of Dept. of Interior National Park Service, to Secretary's Advisory Board on Nat'l. Parks, etc., Dec. 29, 1970. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 2. Part One of the National Park System Plan History. U.S. Dept. of Interior, National Park Service, 1972. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 3. Part Two of the National Park System Plan History. U.S. Dept. of Interior, National Park Service, 1972. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1. Xerox of City Magazine article: The Courts Enter the Land Development Markteplace by Richard Babcock, Jan. - Feb. 1971 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 2. Jamaica Bay & Kennedy Airport: a Multidisciplinary Environmental Study, Volume 1, Nat'l. Academy of Sciences, Nat'l. Academy of Engineering, Washington, D.C. 1971. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 3. Jamaica Bay & Kennedy Airport: a Multidisciplinary Environmental Study, Volume II, Nat'l. Academy of Science, Nat'l. Academy of Engineering, Washington, D.C., 1971 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 4. Air Pollution, a Special Report. Reprinted from the Los Angeles Times, Jan. 6, 1972. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 5. Annual Report, 1972.The Conservation Foundation. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1. Democracy in the Space. Regional Government Under a California State Plan, special report by California Tomorrow, edited by John W. Abbott, 1973, (two copies). (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 2. Ecology and Social Action by Barry Commoner, The Horace M. Albright Conservation Lectureship, University of California School of Forestry and Conservation, March 1973. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 3. Ocean Pollution. What's Nature Telling Us? by Larry Pryor, reprinted from Los Angeles Times July 26, 1970. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1. California Going, Going... by Samuel E. Wood & Alfred E. Heller, California Tomorrow, 1962. (Box 3)
  - 2. The California Tomorrow Plan, California Tomorrow, 1971, (two copies). (Box 3)
  - 3. A Gathering of Nations; a Time of Purpose, National Parks Centennial Commission, 1973. (Box 3)
  - 4. Our Living Land, U.S. Dept of Interior Environmental Report, Conservation Yearbook Series, Vol. 7, 1971. (Box 3)
  - 5. The Phantom Cities of California, California Tomorrow, 1963. (Box 3)
  - 6. Predator Control - 1971, Advisory Committee on Predata Control, Jan. 1972., (two copies). (Box 3)
  - 7. River of Life, U.S. Dept of Interior Environmental Report, Conservation Yearbook Series, Vol. 6, 1970. (Box 3)
  - 8. The Santa Cruz Mountains Regional Pilot Study. Early Warning System, by Tito Patri, David C. Streatfield and Thomas J. Ingmire, Dept. of Landscape Architecture, U.C. Berkeley, August 1970. (Box 3)
  - 9. The Scenic Route/a Guide for the Designation of an Official Scenic Highway, Dept. of Public Works, State of California. (Box 3)
  - 10. Wilderness Management by Stephen H. Spurr, School of Forestry, U.C. Berkeley, May 3, 1966. (Box 3)
  - 11. Graves, John & Watkins, T.H. The Water Hustlers, Sierra Club, 1971. (Box 3)
  - 12. Jackson, Wes. Man and the Environment, Wm. C. Brown Co. Publishers, 1971. (Box 3)
  - 1. Binder containing: a) Statement for the Advisory Board Proposed Longfellow National Historic Site, Sept. 19, 1962,b) Summary of Discussions with Howard I. Chapelle, Marine Architect and Naval Historian Regarding the Authentication and Documentation of the U.S.F., Constellation, c) Department of the Interior Departmental Manual, Jan. 12., 1962,d) Printed memorandum from the White House, Washington to Heads of Executive Departments and Agencies: Preventing Conflicts of Interest on the Part of Advisors and Consultants to the Government, Feb. 9, 1962,e) Memo from Dept. of Interior - National Park Service to Advisory Board on Nat'l. Parks, Historic Sites, Buildings and Monuments re: Revision of rules and regulations governing the Advisory Board, Sept. 13, 1962,f) National Park Service - Administrative Manual, Organization Volume, Amendment No. 22 Dec. 7, 1960(two copies) g) Nat'l. Park Service - Administrative Manual, Organization Volume, Amendment No. 47, June 18, 1962,h) Nat'l. Park Service Restoration Policy Statement, Feb. 24, 1956,i) ca 540 Status Reports of the Advisory Board on Nat'l. Parks (Box 4)
  - 2. Audubon, Vol. 71, No. 1, Jan. 1969. (Box 4)
  - 3. Campus Report Supplement, No. 18, March 29, 1971. (Box 4)
  - 4. Catalyst: Vol. 1, No. 1, Spring 1970;Vol. 1, No. 2, Summer 1970;Vol. III, No. 1, 1973;Vol. III, No. 2, 1973. (Box 4)
  - 1. Cry California: Vol. 1, No. 3, Summer 1966;Vol. 1, No. 4, Fall 1966;Vol. 5, No. 1, Winter 1969/70;Vol. 6, No. 2, Spring 1971;Vol. No. 4, Fall 1971;Vol. 8, No. 1, Winter 1972/73;Vol. 8, No. 2, Spring 1973;Vol. 8, No. 3, Summer 1973(two copies); Vol. 7, No. 3, (Cryy California - The California Tomorrow Plan) Summer 1972. (Box 5)
  - 2. Destination USA - Volumes 1-6, June 1973.Cover letter from Charles S. Thomas, Chairman of Nat'l. Tourism Resources Review Commission, to Wallace Stegner, June 27, 1973.TL, enclosed with Volume 1. (Box 5)
  - 3. Exploration 1972,The School of American Research, 1972. (Box 5)
  - 4. Historic Preservation, July - Sept. 1972, Oct. - Dec. 1972. (Box 5)
  - 5. The Living Wilderness: Vol. 16 No. 38, Autumn 1951;Vol. 18, No. 45, Summer 1953;No. 78, Autumn - Winter. 1961 - 1962;Vol. 34 No. 110 Summer 1970;Vol. 34 No. 112, Winter 1970-71Vol. 35 No. 113, Spring 1971. (Box 5)
  - 1. The Living Wilderness: Vol. 35 No. 115, Autumn 1971(two copies); Vol. 36 No. 118, Summer 1972;Vol. 36 No. 119, Autumn 1972;Vol. 36 No. 120, Winter 1972-1973;Vol. 37 No. 121, Spring 1973. (Box 6)
  - 2. Motorland, Vol. 93, No. 6, November/ December 1972. (Box 6)
  - 3. The Nature Conservancy News: Vol. 21, No. 2, Summer 1970;Vol. 22, No. 4, Fall 1972;Vol. 22, No. 1, Winter 1972. (Box 6)
  - 4. Sierra Club Bulletin: Vol. 57, No. 8, Sept. 1972;Vol. 57, No. 9, Oct. - Nov. 1972;Vol. 57, Nov 10, Dec. 1972;Vol. 58, No. 1, Jan. 1973Vol. 58, No. 2, Feb. 1973;Vol. 58, No. 3, March 1973;Vol. 58, No. 4, April 1973;Vol. 58, No. 5, May 1973;Vol. 58, No. 7, July - Aug. 1973;Vol. 58, No. 19, Nov. - Dec. 1973;Vol. 58, No. 1A, Jan. 1, 1973. (Box 6)
  - 5. TRAVEL & LEISURE, Vol. 4, No. 2, Feb. 1974. (Box 6)
  - 6. Letter - George Marshall to David Brower re. greeting cards, Jan 4 1965.Typed carbon (Box 6)